(+57) 300-782-1311 oquendojair10@gmail.com LinkedIn I Portafolio

Frontend Developer with +4 years of experience developing Frontend Javascript applications with React.js, Next.js Framework, Redux.js, TailwindCSS, SASS or Bootstrap and Backend with Node.js, express. js and MongoDB, I have great capacity for solving problems related to web, I have developed E-Commerce with payment gateway integration, Landing page, finally I have deployed applications on Vercel, Heroku and AWS platforms, blockchain with Ethers.js, Smart Contracts, Solidity or Binance API and virtual environments with Three.js integrated with blockchain networks

EXPERIENCE

Capital Investment (capitalinvestmenttm.com) Medellín, Antioquia,

Chief Technology Officer —November, 2021-Actualidad

Establishing project specifications and technical direction, Creating a framework of technical standards and procedures, In charge of helping the company use technology efficiently and profitably, Create a technological strategy of the company Supervise the IT infrastructure to ensure functionality.

Web3 Frontend —November, 2021-February, 2023

Front-end Blockchain Developer, Support in project management and analysis of requirements for Web3 and Blockchain applications, integration and implementation with web3.js, ethers.js, MetaMask, Samart Contract or Solidity.

Technologies: React.js, Next.js, TailwindCSS, Vercel, Solidity, Ethers.js Web3.js, Remix, Smart Contracts, Serverless, Cl/CD, Design System

BancaCrypto Medellín, Antioquia, Web3 Frontend — October, 2021-November, 2023

Front-end Blockchain Developer, Support in project management and analysis of requirements for Web3 and Blockchain applications, integration and implementation with web3.js, ethers.js, MetaMask, Samart Contract or Solidity.

Technologies: React.js, Next.js, TailwindCSS, Vercel, Solidity, Ethers.js Web3.js, Remix, Smart Contracts, Serverless, CI/CD, Design System

DrakeTech (draketch.ca) Ontario, Canadá, Frontend — September, 2021-October, 2022

Front-end developer, web application layout with Ant Design and Bootstrap, integration with APIs and implementation with React and Redux, support in project management and requirements analysis for software implementation.

Technologies: React.js, Redux,js, Javascript, JSON, JWT, Web API Ant Design, Bootstrap, Git, Git flow, Microfrontend, Design system

Startups Lab - Agencia (startupslabagencia.co), Frontend — August, 2019-Septiembre, 2021

Frontend developer, web page and web application designer and integration of APIs with the Frontend.

- Reduce web site delivery time to the customer by 80% thanks to Vercel
- Reduce layout time by 40% with Tailwind CSS
- Increased development efficiency by 70% thanks to Git flow

Technologies: Next.js, React.js, TailwindCSS, Bootstrap, Vercel, Serverless, CI/CD

PROJECTS

Academy- academy-nu.vercel.app - March, 2023

financial courses platform by Bancacrypto.

Technologies: Next.js, React.js, Tailwind CSS, express.js, MongoDB, Vercel, Paytoshi, ethers.js

Paytoshi Commerce - paytoshi-commerce.vercel.app - November, 2022

Test e-commerce to accept cryptocurrencies payments, integrating Paytoshi payment processor.

Technologies: Next.js, React.js, Tailwind CSS, express.js, MongoDB, Vercel, Paytoshi, ethers.js

Personal Portfolio - oquendo.vercel.app - July, 2022

Web portfolio with my information.

Technologies: Next.js, React.js, Tailwind CSS, Vercel

Paytoshi – paytoshi.vercel.app - July, 2022

Test to accept payments with cryptocurrencies, integrating the payment processor.

Technologies: Next.js, React.js, Tailwind CSS, express.js, MongoDB, Vercel, Paytoshi, ethers.js

Capital Investment - capitalinvestmenttm.com - February, 2021

Investments in the cryptocurrency and traditional markets

Technologies: Next.js, React.js, Tailwind CSS, express.js, MongoDB, Vercel, Paytoshi

Cesquant - cesquant.vercel.app - Abril, 2020

financial courses platform.

Sales of courses to customers were optimized by 90%.

Technologies: Next.js React.js, Node.js, express.js, TailwindCSS, AWS S3, Vercel

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Javascript, CSS, SASS, HTML

Frameworks and Tools: Advanced: React, Next.js, Vercel, TailwindCSS, Bootstrap, JSON, Web API, Serverless, Design System, Intermediate: Node.js. Git, Gitflow, MongoDB, express.js, AWS, Redux.js, JWT, SASS, CI/CD, Microfrontend, Basic:

Angular 2+, GraphQL, Typescript, Docker, Python

Languages: Español

EDUCATION

Graphic Design, *January, 2017 - November, 2018* Instituto Tecnológico San Agustín, Montería - Córdoba

Computer Engineer July, 2011 - July, 2014

Universidad Pontificia Bolivariana, Montería - Córdoba